# Vance Faulkner

# SimpleObjects.io | vpfaulkner@gmail.com | (423) 645-2488

## Summary

Ruby on Rails engineer, strong problem-solver, and customer advocate.

Experienced in front-end and back-end development with a bias towards TDD, agile development, and continuous deployment. Proponent of simple, well-designed solutions and comfortable in fast-moving, distributed teams where self-management is expected. Regularly deals with issues of concurrency, distributed systems, customer support, and scale.

## **Technologies**

Back-end: Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Sidekiq, Rspec, Capybara

Datastore: MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Redis

Front-end: HTML, Javascript, CSS, SASS, jQuery, AJAX, Websockets, Bootstrap, Foundation

Infrastructure: Linux/Unix, AWS, DigitalOcean, Docker, Nginx, Codeship, Heroku

Monitoring: Rollbar, Graylog, Grafana, New Relic, StatsD, Kibana

Development: Git, Github, JIRA, Trello, Vim

## Experience

# Software Engineer I Validic

Durham, NC / Remote | December 2014 — Present

Rails engineer primarily focused on our partner and mobile API

- Implemented our partner and mobile API which, combined, now handle 6+ million requests/day from data sources such as HealthKit on iOS and partner healthcare companies
- Cut API implementation time by 70% by building a developer portal (partner.validic.com)
- One of four engineers who dramatically stabilized our system by addressing technical debt during our first year. Cut the number of monthly support tickets in half after 8 months.

#### Student I The Iron Yard

Durham, NC | August 2014 — December 2014

Participated in a three month Ruby on Rails class while on a leave of absence.

# Growth Strategist I Validic

Durham, NC | August 2013 — August 2014

2nd full-time hire for startup now with 60+ employees and handling 50+ million requests/day

- Helped scale sales by leading sales engineering and marketing analytics
- Established operations including onboarding, CRM integrations, account management, etc.

#### Open Source

rails-sandbox.com | https://github.com/vpfaulkner/rails\_sandbox

Developed web app aimed at promoting Rails conventions by generating Rails code

#### Education

## University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill

Bachelor of Arts in Economics; minor in English Literature; Graduated with Distinction